<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Capsule App</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="motion">
        \nDistance and Displacement  \n\n
The magnitude of the length covered by a moving object is called distance. It has no direction.
Displacement is the shortest distance between two points or the distance between the starting and final positions with respect to time. It has magnitude as well as direction.

Displacement can be zero, but distance cannot.\n

\n

Magnitude\n\n
Magnitude is the size or extent of a physical quantity. In physics, we have scalar and vector quantities.

Scalar quantities are only expressed as magnitude. E.g.: time, distance, mass, temperature, area, volume

Vector quantities are expressed in magnitude as well as the direction of the object. E.g.: Velocity, displacement, weight, momentum, force, acceleration, etc./n

\nTime, Average Speed and Velocity\n
\nTime and speed\n\n
Time is the duration of an event that is expressed in seconds. Most physical phenomena occur with respect to time. It is a scalar quantity.\n

Speed is the rate of change in distance. If a body covers a certain distance in a certain amount of time, its speed is given by



The instantaneous speed is the speed of an object at a particular moment in time.\n

Average speed is stated as the distance covered by the object within a period of time.\n

Average speed = Total distance travelled / Total time taken\n

\n
\n
\nAverage Speed and Instantaneous Speed\n\n
\nIt is defined as the total distance travelled divided by the total time elapsed.	It is defined as the speed at a particular instant of time.
It is constant.	It is not constant.
Measured by calculating the speed for an entire journey.\n	It is measured by a speedometer.
\nExample: A car travelling with a speed of 60 kmph. Thus, the average speed of the car is 60 km an hour.	Example: A car travelling at a certain speed at an instant of time can be given by a speedometer.
Uniform motion and Non-uniform motion
When an object covers equal distances in equal intervals of time, it is in uniform motion.
\n\n
\nExamples of Uniform Motion
\nMovement of the ceiling fan’s blades.
\nMotion of Earth around the sun
\nPendulum with equivalent amplitude on either side
\nWhen an object covers unequal distances in equal intervals of time, it is said to be in non-uniform motion.
\nBouncing ball
\nRunning horse
\nMoving train
\n
\nVelocity\n
The Rate of change of displacement is velocity. It is a vector quantity. Here the direction of motion is specified.



\nInstantaneous velocity is the rate of change of position for a time interval which is very small, i.e. almost zero. In more simple words, the velocity of an object at a given instant of time is known as instantaneous velocity.

Average velocity is defined as the displacement (∆x) divided by the time intervals (∆t) in which the displacement occurs.


\n\n\n
Average Velocity\n	Instantaneous Velocity
Average velocity is defined as the displacement (∆x) divided by the time intervals (∆t) in which the displacement occurs.	Instantaneous velocity is the rate of change of position for a time interval which is very small, i.e. almost zero.
Average velocity is calculated by dividing the rate of displacement by the time elapsed.	Instantaneous velocity is calculated by dividing displacement by time at that instant.
\nIf Jack took a total of 1 hour to travel 10 km from his house to school, then his average velocity will be 10 km/hr.	In Jack’s case, on his way to school, while he is sitting and waiting for the train to pass, his instantaneous velocity will be zero. Though the instantaneous velocity was zero for a small part of the journey, the average velocity will not be zero.

\nAcceleration\n
\nThe rate of change of velocity is called acceleration. It is a vector quantity. In non-uniform motion, velocity varies with time, i.e., the change in velocity is not 0. It is denoted by “a”

\nAcceleration = Change in Velocity / Time
\n\n\n
Uniform Circular Motio\nn\n
\nUniform Circular Motion
\nIf an object moves in a circular path with uniform speed, its motion is called uniform circular motion.
\nVelocity changes as direction keeps changing.
\nAcceleration is constant.
\nThe uniform circular velocity is given by the following formula:

\n\n
\nUniform Circular Motion

\nUniform Circular Motion Examples
\nThe motion of artificial satellites around the Earth is an example of uniform circular motion.
\nThe motion of electrons around its nucleus.
\nThe motion of blades of the windmills.
\nThe tip of the second hand of a watch with a circular dial shows uniform circular motion.</string>
</resources>